

Contact

Phone 0775458209

Email

faouzi.laadjal99@gmail.com

Address Lot n°210 Baraki, Algiers.

Portfolio
https://faouzi-laadjal.vercel.app/

LinkedIn Faouzi Laadjal

General Skills

- PLC Programming (Tla portal / step7)
- Hmi & Scada Design (WinCC)
- Electrical Shematics (Eplan P8 Electric)
- Web developpemnt (Vs Code)
- Office tools

Programming Skills

Ladder / STL / SCL

•••

Html / CSS/ JS

••••

Bootstrap / ReactJs

•••

Languages

Arabic $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$ English $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$

Laadjal Faouzi

Automation Engineering Student & Front Web developer

Profile

Hello, my name is Faouzi Laadjal, i'm a 23 years old highly motivated and passionate Industry & Process Automation student & Front End web developer on my free time. always seeks to acquire new knowledge and develop my skills, Strong desire and big determination to succeed in my field of work

Experience

O January 2022- Present

Freelancer

Front End Developer

 $Intermediate\ Web\ developement\ skills\ \ Checkout\ my\ intresting\ Work\ on\ My\ Portfolio\ .$

June 2022- August 2022

LM Electric I Les Eucalyptus, Algiers, Algeria

Intenrship | Automation Engineer

Spent 2 months learning various industrial electrical skills, mainly:

- -Simulation of a pumping station with two submersible pumps of 4KW.
- -Simulation of a Wastewater treatment plant (biological treatment part) of the city of Sidi AICH.
- -Creation of the electrical diagram for the manual operation mode (by push buttons) & automatic operation mode (with a PLC) under EPLAN Electric.
- -Programming of the automatic operations and diffrent modes as well as the safety operation (programming language SCL/Ladder).
- -Make HMI/SCADA interface using WinCC.
- -Electrical wiring of a small bench test with diffrent Hardwares(PLC,VFD,.....)
- -Various test on a motor using a modular frequency converter SINAMICS G120.

March 2022

Groupe GICA I Meftah, Blida, Algeria

Internship Trainee

Internship in concrete-production factory, the objective was to:

- -Understand the cement manufacturing process and the supervision with the DCS system.
- -Identification of the different instrumentations and cabinets of power, control and compensation.
- -Identification of the different electrical components and the different type of communication buses in the control room cabinet (S7-400, Modbus, Ethernet,).

Education

Masters in Industry & Process Automation

September 2022 - Present

Houari Boumediene University of Science and Technology, Algiers.

Licence in Automation

September 2018 - July 2021

Houari Boumediene University of Science and Technology, Algiers.

-Virtual control of the operative parts of the industrial systems of the software " ITS PLC " $\,$

Elementary Math Baccalaureate

June 2018

Baraki, Algiers, Algeria.